[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Good morning, good evening-- good afternoon,
brothers and sisters.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
It's right after 12, so--
Thank you for having me.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
It's great coming back home.
It's been three to four years already.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And I'm glad to be able to share what's going on in Taiwan
with you guys.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Yeah.
So I could read the scriptural verses.
The scriptural verses is found in John chapter 4,
verse 43 to 54.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So verse 43-- "After the two days he left for Galilee,
now Jesus himself hath pointed out
that a prophet has no honor in his own country.
When he arrived in Galilee, the Galileans welcomed him.
They had seen all that he had done in Jerusalem
at the Passover festival, for they also had been there."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
46-- "Once more he visited Cana in Galilee,
where he had turned the water into wine.
And there was a certain royal official
whose son lay sick at Capernaum.
When this man heard that Jesus had arrived in Galilee
from Judea, he went to him and begged him
to come and heal his son, who was close to death.
'Unless you people see signs and wonders,'
Jesus told him, 'you will never believe.'"
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
49-- "The royal official said, 'Sir, come down before my child
dies.
Go,' Jesus replied.
'Your son will live.'
The man took Jesus at his word and departed."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
50-- "While he was still on the way,
his servant met him with the news that his boy was living.
When he inquired as to the time when his son got better,
they said to him, 'Yesterday at one in the afternoon,
the fever left him.'
Then the father realized that this was the exact time
at which Jesus had said to him, 'Your son will live.'
So he and his whole household believed
this was the second sign Jesus performed after coming
from Judea to Galilee."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Yeah, I just want to use this passage to highlight
the situation and my work in Taiwan.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So in Taiwan, basically, you see this is a small city.
It's called Pingtung City.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
On the right side, the gate is down.
But you see that there's a church there.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In the church, there's around like 30 to 40 brothers
and sisters.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
That room is basically the whole church.
And I work mainly as a youth pastor.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I really love enjoying hanging out with kids.
But when you become the youth pastor at 40,
it's kind of difficult sometimes.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
As a youth pastor, we also do a lot of camps.
I also am a host.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Yeah, I also pass out lunch.
That's right.
And lead Bible study.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I did a wedding or two.
I even do chameleon.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I also wash the toilet.
In the church plant, you got to do everything.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
There is not anything that is beneath me.
There's no work that's beneath me.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So today, I want to talk about two kinds
of faith in this passage.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The first one is shallow faith.
So in the beginning of verse 43 right here,
John gives us an introduction of what is this passage about.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In verse 43, actually, Jesus is actually
traveling home from Galilee.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
He was in Jerusalem for the Passover festival.
And he purposely went through Samaria
to tell the Samarians about his identity.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Now he's back home in Galilee.
Now in 44, the apostle John said a prophet
has no honor in his own country.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But as we go to 45, it says the Galilean welcomed him.
But at face value, brothers and sisters,
there seems to be some sort of conflict here.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Because in the synoptic Gospels, Jesus
used the phrase a prophet without honor
in his own hometown too.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
He used it when people reject him.
So actually, there's no conflict here.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In this, John, in 44, when he says that,
he's actually telling us, be prepared.
These people's faith, they're not really that deep.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They're following Jesus for the wrong reasons.
So as we go to 46, 47, 48, this is
where the confrontation begins.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In the beginning of 46, once again,
it's purpose is to state that Jesus came back
to Cana in Galilee.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This is where he turned water into wine, his first miracle.
It's kind of give us an impression
that this miracle is well-known in this region,
in this village.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So as we know right now, most of the Galileans
right now heard about Jesus.
He's kind of making a name for himself.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And right now, in the second part of 46,
it introduced a human knee where the official's son is sick.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The official, like any human being,
would do anything to save his son.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So once he heard that Jesus is in Galilee,
he came and begged Jesus to heal his son.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Now, think about our brothers and sisters.
As an official, you have a lot of authority
and power during that time.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
He could just command Jesus, you better come and heal my son.
If not, I'll put you in jail or I'll kill you.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Why would he come and beg a Jew?
I feel like he already exhausted all his ways and all
his connections, and he still can't find healing for his son.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
You can see, you can have all the money and power
that you want, but death is still
within everyone's destiny.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Only Jesus proved the wrong through his empty grave.
See, in verse 48, this is how Jesus responded.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In English, the you is actually plural.
Jesus is not just responding to the official.
He's responding to the crowd also.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Jesus said, you believe in me because of my miracle
and the sensation that you get to see.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They see Jesus as a miracle worker,
and he became famous right now.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
See, Jesus brought pride and recognition
back to his hometown.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
See, in Judah, the capital, they look down
on the people in Galilee.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Right now, Jesus became a celebrity,
and this crowd has had a chance to follow him right now.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Think about the latest trend.
I know the one on the left is Taylor Swift.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And it's one of the hottest singer right now, right?
Everyone is-- the fans of a Taylor Swift fan
are called Swifties.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But I don't know anything about Taylor Swift.
I only know Michael Jordan.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I know where he was born.
I know the name of his mother, father.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I know the names of his three children.
I know all his accomplishments.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But I don't know him.
I don't have a personal relationship with him.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So we go back to verse 44.
Where John said, a prophet has no honor in his hometown.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
It's actually very difficult for the Galileans to accept Jesus.
Think about it.
Some of them probably watched Jesus grow up.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Some of them probably knew his family, played with him.
It is very difficult to submit to someone
that you know so well.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I'll give you an example.
My youngest uncle, I taught him everything about computers.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
He didn't even know how to open a computer at that time.
But this time when I came home, he
said he got something to teach me about computers.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Something in my mind saying something is wrong.
How can that be?
I taught you everything.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But he actually has something new to teach me.
But it feels so weird.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But I tell you, brothers and sisters,
the Samaritans did not have that feeling.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They did not require any really miracles.
They believed Jesus based on his words.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In verse 42, this is what they said.
"Jesus is the Savior of the world."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
See, brothers and sisters, these signs
were meant to validate Jesus' claim of being the Messiah.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
That he's the son of God so people
can put their trust in him.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
These signs were intended to inspire faith,
not to please the people.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
There is no authentic relationship,
and the people don't have to make any commitments.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
These people's faith are shallow.
They don't know Jesus personally.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They only want Jesus to perform for them.
They don't even care who is Jesus,
or they don't want any relationship.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I can tell you, most people in Taiwan are like this.
Most people come to church for different reasons.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They don't see Jesus as Lord and Savior.
They see Jesus as more like a healer or a genie.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I totally understand that feeling.
Because when I first came to church,
it has nothing to do with Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I came to church because of basketball and meeting people.
Jesus is far from my mind.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
If you take a look, certain people come for a lunch.
Some people want to practice English.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But they tell me, don't talk to me about Jesus.
I said, OK.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But I cannot not share Jesus.
That is part of my life.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Some people come for music and English lessons.
I did not want to make these lessons, actually.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But the parents said, if you have nothing academic or good
to learn, then my kids are not coming to church.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
That's why my wife had to teach ukulele,
and I had to teach English.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
We had a chance to break down an altar.
But overall, sometimes, even when brothers and sisters
become Christians, their life is not transformed.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In their heart, they just transfer one idol to another.
Jesus became another idol for them.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
See, they only want the blessing,
but not the relationship, brothers and sisters.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
My question is, how about us?
Is this what we do also?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
That's why I don't want us to be fans.
I want us to be disciples.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But how is a disciple different from being a fan?
Therefore, let's look at how real faith looks like,
which brings my second point.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
My second point is Atlantic faith.
Let's go on.
In verse 49, unlike the crowd, the official is very desperate
at this time.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Think about ourself.
When are we closest to God?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
During our peaceful time.
When everything is going well.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I'm sorry to say, that's when we're always farthest from God.
It is usually during trials.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In verse 50, if you see in other gospel stories,
this is the outcome.
Usually, this is what happened in other gospel story.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
After enough pleading, usually Jesus
will heal or take care of that person's problem.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But this time, Jesus did not do that.
My speculation is this.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Jesus did not want to please these fans.
Because they were looking for another show.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And Jesus wanted to also force the official
to choose if he's willing to trust in Jesus
without seeing a miracle.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
It is not normal for people to do things that are illogical.
An example.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In Taiwan, if the doctor tells a patient
to go home without medicine, that is a no-no.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Even if I have a common cold, there
will be five different types of medicine to bring home.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
It got to a point that people feel like,
if there is no medicine, that means you're not effective.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
See, brothers and sisters, I need something
to look at, to grasp onto.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So if I were the official, I would have the same feeling.
It also shifts the official's mindset, his mentality,
from thinking about a quick fix to his problem.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Think about when you're stressed out for your job,
for your family, or even your kids.
You want to fix the problem right away.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
You want Jesus to give you a pill,
and just swallow it, and fix the problem.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But in this story, Jesus did not give the official a pill.
He gave the official his word, which is to go home.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
See, with no other choice, the official
has to decide to believe in Jesus' word.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And this belief is a sign of true progression of faith.
See, true faith is not just based on observed miracle,
but based on the word of God.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And his action, by starting his journey home,
shows that he's consistent with the faith.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
See, in verse 51, as the official is almost home,
his servant came out to meet him with good news
that his son is alive.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Assuming the official is happy, I
would think he would normally focus all his attention
on his son.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
He might want to see him and spend time with him.
Or even find a doctor to see if he's truly well.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Instead, he focuses his attention back to Jesus' word.
Sorry.
In 52, when asked about the time,
the servant said it was yesterday at 1 o'clock.
Yesterday at 1 PM.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Based on this, the official spent a night traveling back
to his hometown.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Think about it, brothers and sisters.
This night will be a very, very difficult night.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
He has to wrestle with the decision because he wasn't sure
what Jesus said would come true or not.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But it is during this time, these struggles,
that God will strengthen us and help
us to put more trust in him.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
At last, he verified Jesus' word,
and it was proved to be true.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In verse 53, unlike the crowd, he
was willing to make a real commitment to follow Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The miracle helped push him through with his faith
in trusting in Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
He didn't just stop there.
He also told the good news to his family.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
See, brothers and sisters, true faith is a progression,
and it's not a one-time deal.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
God will always give us trials in different seasons
of our life so we could put trust in him more.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Throughout my three years, there are not many people
who's willing to do that.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But because of time-wise, I only got two examples for you.
First one is I have a group of brothers and sisters.
This is a Bible study that I host.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And they asked to study the Bible like a year or two ago.
And I told them, let's end the Bible study this January.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Because I was about to end my time
with this church in February.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And February is Chinese New Year.
And I thought they would have a lot of stuff to take care of.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They said, Steve, Chinese New Year is different from before.
We don't take care of stuff anymore.
We just go out to eat.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They said, since you're here for another month,
we want to do more Bible study.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
You know, that's the most happiest thing for my job.
I really enjoy doing that as a missionary.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Another is a family.
The girl's name is Lucy.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This family came to our church through our summer camp,
our VBS camp.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They were very poor.
Because they spent all their money on their health.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And this is not the first church they came to.
After a while, when we get to know each other a little bit
more, she told me this story, the mom.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Is that at one of my church, the minister said this to me.
Do you know why you and your whole family is sick?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Because you don't believe in Jesus.
Man, that really hurt me, you know that?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Because that's not the true gospel.
And it got to a point that Lucy, the girl,
was eating congee for the whole month.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And they were asking us, is there
any stuff that you have in the church refrigerator?
Can we take them?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I said, take everything you want.
And then we went home, different ways.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But that night during dinner, I was really hot.
I was really mad.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And I was mad during eating hot pot.
So I was extra hot.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
My mind was, I want to find this minister and beat him up.
But another thought came to me.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I told my wife and my family, we are going to the supermarket
right now.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
We are going to load up the cart with grocery,
and we're going to bring it to their house.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And we told him, this is from the church.
This is from Jesus.
This is unconditional.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
After a couple of weeks--
She was willing to ask, Steve Shirley, what is the gospel?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I feel like they're willing to ask this question.
Is this that they saw a difference in our lives?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But brothers and sisters, I want to know, how do you see Jesus?
Is he a celebrity, or he's your Lord?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
If Jesus is your Lord, does your life matches the gospel?
You see, missions is an integrated part
of our Christian life.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
You are a missionary in your sphere of influence.
See, the only difference between me and you guys
is that we serve in a different place.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Remember the Great Commission?
Basically, it's to go to all nations
and proclaim the gospel, right?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But some of us might be saying, I don't know enough.
I'm not capable of doing that.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I can tell you, I have the same feeling.
I don't really have much talents.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I don't know a lick of music.
I'm not a good speaker, actually.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I don't have really much skills to teach kids.
But I want you to know, God don't
use those who are talented a lot of times.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
God use those who say they are available.
Because God will supply you with the resource
to get the job done.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
My thing is that in your company,
don't your company supply you with the basic resource
to get to do your job?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But one thing I don't want you, besides the Greek mission,
I don't want you to forget about one other thing.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Which is the great commandment.
Which is to love God with all your heart, soul, mind,
and strength, right?
But the second one is to love people
like you would love yourself.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Don't preach the gospel like you're giving a sales pitch.
Love that person.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
What's going to happen in the next four years, brothers
and sisters?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I will be moving to a new church.
We are going to-- oops.
I live in Kaohsiung, but we're going to move a little bit
to Chiayi.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So this is our church.
It's called a grace place.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
It's an even more rural area than where I was before.
This is some of the things I will be doing.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
You pastor again.
Yeah, and that's something I really enjoy doing.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And I could do this every day.
Yeah, but God continue to allow me with the energy.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But this is the church that we will be in.
Another small church, about 30 to 40 people.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Typical church in Taiwan, that's how big it is.
Again, I'm going there to learn how to be a better pastor.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Yeah, that's one thing is that I need
to practice my Chinese, Mandarin.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I feel comfortable speaking to you in Mandarin
when we're just having a dialogue, an informal dialogue.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But formal speaking is another level.
But I don't want to hide in my comfort zone.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I want to be able to tell the Taiwanese people
the gospel in their native language.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This is what I did for 15 minutes,
telling my testimony in Mandarin.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The Mandarin is really bad.
But my mentality is I don't care.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
I need to keep practicing.
I need to keep messing up.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
That's the way how I will improve.
Because I need to tell the people about the gospel
in the native language.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Thank you, brothers and sisters.
Thank you.
This is my sharing.
And I thank you for always praying for us
as we are in the mission field.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]